

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Bredgata 24D, 222 21, Lund, Sweden

"Do not be smart when writing code, write boring code creating exiting products."

Summary _

Educated as a Physicist, employed as an Embedded Systems Software Developer, currently working with Python, Scala, and Typescript as a Backend Software Engineer. In my previous assignment I worked in Linux and C/C++ on network segmentation solutions for critical infrastructure with the IT security company Advenica.

In my spare time, I like to go hiking, read interesting articles and tutorials, work on private programming projects, and tinker with computers. I have a raspberry pi running a bunch of services like media server, git repositories, and file hosting. Many of my skills originate from learning in my spare time. My natural habitate is in Linux creating exiting things with C/C++ and Python.

Recently I have grown more and more interested in concepts like continuous integration. This CV is for exampled automatically built using docker in a GitHub action and then if successfully built, published to https://cv.emijoh.se.

Skills

Programming Python, Linux, Scala, Continious Integration, TypeScript, C/C++, LaTeX, git

Machine Learning TensorFlow, Keras, Google Cloud

Languages Swedish, English

Experience

Backend Software Engineer

Malmö, Sweden Feb. 2018 - present

Undisclosed

- Working with Python, Scala, and TypeScript.
 Taking a technical leadership role in the team driving code quality and increased developer productivity and quality of deliverables.
- Learned a lot about producing and releasing high quality software at fast pace in an environment with many stakeholders and unknowns.

Embedded Systems Sofware Engineer

Malmö, Sweden

ADVENICA

Sep. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Levering Linux and C/C++ knowledge, developing support for new network protocols in network segmentation products for critical infrastructure.
- Improved ability to write perfomant, safe, high quality C/C++ code under tight deadlines.

Full Stack Web Application

Lund, Sweden

PRIVATE PROJECT

Mar. 2017

• Created a proof-of-concept "Wikipedia band name generator" web site levering public APIs, python code, cloud hosting, and flask to automatically generate silly band names and cover art.

IOS and Desktop QT Application

Lund, Sweden

PRIVATE PROJECT

Sep. 2016

- My interest in automation resulted in that creating a Sudoku solver app seems more fun than solving Sudoku manually so that is what I did.
- · Learned about connecting and separating back end a front end logic as well as the QT framework

Employment

AFRY (Formerly ÅF) - Embedded Systems

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Malmö, Sweden

Sep. 2018 - Present

Lund University, Faculty of Engineering

PROJECT ASSISTANT

Jun. 2018 – Aug. 2018

Lund University, Faculty of Engineering

Exercise Tutor

Lund, Sweden

Lund, Sweden

Sep. 2017 - Nov. 2017

Education _

Lund University

Lund, Sweden

M.SC IN PHYSICS Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2018

Focus on theoretical and mathematical physics.

Lund University

Lund, Sweden

B.Sc IN PHYSICS Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

Focus on computational and mathematical physics.

Honors & Awards _____

NanoLund Junior Scientist Ideas Award, For M.Sc project exploring novel applications of

NanoLund

machine learning.

Stockholm

2013 **Swedish Junior Water Price.**, Award for high school degree project.

International Water

Institute.

Writing _

Teaching a Neural Network Quantum Mechanics. A Deep Learning Approach to the N-Representability Problem.

M.Sc thesis.

AUTHOR

2018

https://lup.lub.lu.se/student-papers/search/publication/8951887

Numerical simulations of contact geometry effects on transport properties of semiconductor nanowires

B.Sc thesis.

Author

2016

https://lup.lub.lu.se/student-papers/search/publication/8878322